

# Subhransu **Maharana**

**Full Stack Engineer** 



+91 9886326216



subhransumaharana@gmail.com



subhnet.github.io



https://github.com/subhnet



Sarjapura Road, Bengaluru, India 560035



# **ABOUT ME**

An Experienced Full-Stack Developer with over six years of experience in designing, developing and implementing applications and solutions using range of technologies. Always keen to learn new technologies, Following best Quality Practices by applying Design Patterns, on-time Delivery, and looking to take more leadership over project delivery.



## **WORK EXPERIENCES**

## **Full Stack Engineer**

June, 2019 - present

## **Adobe Systems**

- Worked on building executive-focused Adobe analytics dashboards for Adobe's top digital marketing clients and developing custom web applications end to end to solve various customer needs.
- Designed and Developed an Automation Framework that automates the process of onboarding a client to Adobe Analytics, Launch, and Target for a Customer Website. This Framework has reduced the Consultant Efforts significantly by 90% and is now used across other teams.
- Developing serverless and event-driven applications based on events originating from various Adobe services using Adobe I/O runtime, events.
- Responsible for building an Automation framework for AEM CM frontend Deployment using Gulp Scripts, Github API, Github Actions, which in turn enabled my teammates to reduce the development effort.
- Experience on building workflow DAGs using Apache Airflow
- Worked with tight deadlines and small consulting budgets to complete major tasks.

Server Side: Node.js, Express.js, Java, Docker, AWS, GraphQL, Apache Openwhisk Client Side: ReactJS, Javascript, HTML, CSS

## **Software Engineer**

March, 2017 - May, 2019

## **Fidelity Investments**

- Responsible for upgrading the codebase to Angular UI and Back-end in JAVA SpringBoot Restful Services. Develop testable, reusable, and maintainable components/services, integrating Restful APIs.
- Responsible for building a Table Component Framework for eTax Application, which made dynamic content to be easily customizable, focusing on its stability. It was reused across Multiple teams as well.
- Implemented Lazy-Loading, leading to an 85% reduction in web app loading time.
- Identified and suggested new technologies and tools for enhancing product value

## **Project Engineer**

Sept, 2014 - Feb, 2017

## **Wipro Technologies**

Bluedart Website Revamp

- Key Contributor in development and implementation of the project from build-out testing and integration into the production environment.
- Developing SOAP-based Web Services (bottom-up) which internally consumes various third-party vendors and also calls Oracle stored procedures.
- Google Map API Integration with shortest path implementation
- Technologies: LiferayAUI, JAVA, SOAP Webservices, axis2, Javascript, HTML, CSS



# SKILLS

## FRONT END

- ReactJS , AngularJS
- HTML5, CSS
- Javascript(ES6)
- Typescript
- JQuery

## **BACK END**

- Java
- Node.JS, NPM
- ExpressJs
- Spring Framework
- SpringBoot
- MvSQL
- Serverless Framework

#### **DEVOPS**

- AWS. Azure
- Docker
- Apache Openwhisk
- Apache Airflow
- Github Actions

## **MISCELLANEOUS SKILLS**

GraphQL Gulp Git Tomcat NGINX Maven Webpack Babel Rest API Adobe I/O



## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

"On the Spot Award" - Awarded in Fidelity Investments, 2017.

"Individual Award" - Awarded for solving complex framework bugs in Fidelity, 2018.

"Team of the Quarter" - Awarded for contribution in Adobe, 2020 Selected for Adobe Tech Summit'21



## **EDUCATION**

## **B.Tech in Computer Science**

Veer Surendra Sai University of Technology, Burla, Odisha 2010-2014